{"version":1,"data":{"1":{"category":"ACCOUNTING BASIC","question_set":[{"qID":"1.0|hard","question":"Under the accrual basis of accounting, expenses are reported in the accounting period when the","selection":["Cash is paid","Accounts payable","Expense Matches The Revenues Or Is Used Up"],"answer":"Expense Matches The Revenues Or Is Used Up"},{"qID":"1.1|hard","question":"Assets are usually reported on the balance sheet at which amount?","selection":["Cost","Current market value","Expected selling price"],"answer":"Cost"},{"qID":"1.2|hard","question":"Liabilities often have the word __________  in their account title. ","selection":["Revenue","Payable","Cash"],"answer":"Payable"},{"qID":"1.3|hard","question":"Accounting entries involve a minimum of how many accounts? ","selection":["One","Two","Three"],"answer":"Two"},{"qID":"1.4|hard","question":"Assets minus liabilities equals  ","selection":["Drawing","Capital","Stockholders equity or owners equity "],"answer":"Stockholder's equity or owners equity "},{"qID":"1.5|hard","question":"When cash is received, the account Cash will be ","selection":["Debited","Credited","Account Receivable"],"answer":"Debited"},{"qID":"1.6|hard","question":"When a company pays a bill, the account Cash will be","selection":["Debit","Credit","Accounts payable"],"answer":"Credited"},{"qID":"1.7|hard","question":"Entries to expenses such as Rent Expense are usually","selection":["Credits","Adjusting entries","Debits"],"answer":"Debits"},{"qID":"1.8|hard","question":"Entries to revenues accounts such as Service Revenues are usually","selection":["Net income","Debit","Service Income"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"1.9|hard","question":"What will usually cause the liability account Accounts Payable to increase?","selection":["Debits","Credits","Both Debit and Credit"],"answer":"Credits"}]},"2":{"category":"DEBIT AND CREDIT","question_set":[{"qID":"2.0|hard","question":"A company using the accrual method of accounting performed services on account in August. The services were for $2,000 and the company gave the customer credit terms that state the amount is to be paid to the company in September. Assuming that the company prepares monthly income statements, what will be the account debited for $2,000 in August?\n","selection":["Cash","Account receivable","Service revenue"],"answer":"Account receivable"},{"qID":"2.1|hard","question":"A company using the accrual method of accounting performed services on account in August. The services were for $2,000 and the company gave the customer credit terms that state the amount is to be paid to the company in September. Which account should the company credit for $2,000 in August?","selection":["Cash ","Account receivable","Service revenue"],"answer":"Service revenue"},{"qID":"2.2|hard","question":"A company using the accrual method of accounting performed services on account in August. The services were for $2,000 and the company gave the customer credit terms that state the amount is to be paid to the company in September. In September when the company receives the $2,000 from the customer, which account should the company debit?","selection":["Cash","Account receivable","Service revenue"],"answer":"Cash"},{"qID":"2.3|hard","question":"A company using the accrual method of accounting performed services on account in August. The services were for $2,000 and the company gave the customer credit terms that state the amount is to be paid to the company in September. In September when the company receives the $2,000 from the customer, which account should the company credit?","selection":["Cash","Account receivable","Service revenue"],"answer":"Account receivable"},{"qID":"2.4|hard","question":"What is the normal balance  of :  ACCOUNTS PAYABLE ","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"2.5|hard","question":"What is the normal balance of : CASH ","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"2.6|hard","question":"What is the normal balance of : CAPITAL","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"2.7|hard","question":"What is the normal balance of : SUPPLIES","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"2.8|hard","question":"What is the normal balance of : PREPAID INSURANCE","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Debit"},{"qID":"2.9|hard","question":"What is the normal balance of : SERVICE REVENUE","selection":["Debit","Credit",""],"answer":"Credit"}]},"3":{"category":"CHART OF ACCOUNT","question_set":[{"qID":"3.0|hard","question":"The chart of accounts has a list of:","selection":["Names of customers and suppliers","General ledger account names and numbers","Names of each inventory item"],"answer":"General ledger account names and numbers"},{"qID":"3.1|hard","question":"Name the five main categories that the ledger accounts are grouped under:","selection":["Assets, credit cards, liabilities, money, contact cards ","Assets, production, bank register, purchases, sales","Assets, liabilities, equity, income, expenses"],"answer":"Assets, liabilities, equity, income, expenses"},{"qID":"3.2|hard","question":"Which category usually has (but not always!) the most accounts?","selection":["The banking corporation","The 10 richest people of the world","Expenses"],"answer":"Expenses"},{"qID":"3.3|hard","question":"What equation does the chart of accounts tie-in with?","selection":["Accounting equation","Wave equation","The origin of complex numbers"],"answer":"Accounting equation"},{"qID":"3.4|hard","question":"Which category do you think an insurance loan would go under?","selection":["Asset","Liabilities","Expenses"],"answer":"Liabilities"},{"qID":"3.5|hard","question":"Under which category do you think a new, high cost computer would go ? ","selection":["Expenses","Income","Asset"],"answer":"Asset"},{"qID":"3.6|hard","question":"Which category do you think business Travel & Accommodation costs would go under?","selection":["Expenses","Liabilities","Equity"],"answer":"Expenses"},{"qID":"3.7|hard","question":"Which category do you think wages would go under?","selection":["Equity","Expenses","Income"],"answer":"Expenses"},{"qID":"3.8|hard","question":"Which category do you think the website development costs would go under?","selection":["Asset","Expenses","Equity"],"answer":"Asset"},{"qID":"3.9|hard","question":"A customer pays a deposit for work not yet started. Where does this go?","selection":["Income","Asset","Equity"],"answer":"Asset"}]},"4":{"category":"BOOKKEEPING","question_set":[{"qID":"4.0|hard","question":"A listing of the balances in the accounts in order to determine whether debits are equal to credits is a __________ .","selection":["Balance sheet","Trial balance","General ledger"],"answer":"Trial balance"},{"qID":"4.1|hard","question":"The listing of accounts that are available for posting transactions is the \n __________  of accounts. \n","selection":["Chart ","Financial","Basic"],"answer":"Chart"},{"qID":"4.2|hard","question":"When a sale is made on credit, the seller will debit the asset account Accounts \n __________.\n","selection":["Payable","Receivable","Cash"],"answer":"Receivable"},{"qID":"4.3|hard","question":"Asset,  __________ , and stockholders' equity accounts are known as balance sheet accounts.","selection":["Owners equity","Liability","Equity"],"answer":"Liability"},{"qID":"4.4|hard","question":"The separation of duties is part of the internal __________  for safeguarding assets.","selection":["Safety","Controls","Guard"],"answer":"Credit"},{"qID":"4.5|hard","question":"Cash and Accounts Receivable are two examples of accounts that are reported on the classified balance sheet under the heading  ________ asset. ","selection":["Fixed","Current","None-current"],"answer":"Current"},{"qID":"4.6|hard","question":"A __________ entry typically removes an accrual-type adjusting entry that had been recorded in the preceding accounting period. ","selection":["Reconciliation","Reversing","Recording"],"answer":"Reversing"},{"qID":"4.7|hard","question":"The difference between the balance in a company's cash account and its bank statement is documented in the __________ of the bank statement. ","selection":["Reconciliation","Reversing","Recording"],"answer":"Reconciliation"},{"qID":"4.8|hard","question":"The bookkeeping or accounting equation is Assets = Liabilities + Owner's \n __________ . \n","selection":["Income","Equity","Capital"],"answer":"Equity"},{"qID":"4.9|hard","question":"Large corporations should report revenues on their income statements when the __________.","selection":["Cash is received","Revenues are earned","Cash is unreceived"],"answer":"Revenues are earned"}]},"5":{"category":"ACCOUNTING EQUATION","question_set":[{"qID":"5.0|hard","question":"ABC purchases $100 worth of office supplies for inventory and stores them in their storage room. The office supply store gives them an invoice that allows them to pay for them in 15 days (on account).","selection":["Asset increase and Liabilities increase","Asset decrease and Liabilities decrease","Owners equity decrease and Asset decrease"],"answer":"Asset increase and Liabilities Increase"},{"qID":"5.1|hard","question":"ABC places an ad in the local newspaper receives the invoice from the supplier and writes a check for $25 to the newspaper.","selection":["Owners equity increase and Liabilities decrease ","Owners equity decrease and Asset decrease","Service revenue"],"answer":"Owners equity decrease and Asset decrease"},{"qID":"5.2|hard","question":"The owner withdraws cash from the business for personal use : Owner's (or Stockholders') Equity ","selection":["Increase","Decrease","No effect"],"answer":"Decrease"},{"qID":"5.3|hard","question":"The company receives cash from a bank loan : Liabilities ","selection":["Increase","Decrease","No effect"],"answer":"Increase"},{"qID":"5.4|hard","question":"The company purchases equipment with its cash : Asset ","selection":["Increase","Decrease","No effect"],"answer":"Increase"},{"qID":"5.5|hard","question":"ABC purchases five mowers for $10,000 and finances them with a note from the local bank. ","selection":["Asset decrease and Liabilities increase","Asset increase and Owners equity increase","Asset increase and Liabilities increase"],"answer":"Asset increase and Liabilities increase"},{"qID":"5.6|hard","question":"The company purchases land by paying half in cash and signing a note payable for the other half : Owner's (or Stockholders') Equity","selection":["Increase","Decrease","No effect"],"answer":"No effect"},{"qID":"5.7|hard","question":"ABC places an ad in the local newspaper receives the invoice from the supplier and writes a check for $25 to the newspaper.","selection":["Asset increase and Owners equity increase","Owner equity decrease and Asset decrease",""],"answer":"Owners equity decrease and Assets decrease "},{"qID":"5.8|hard","question":"Company X provides consulting services to Client Q in May. Company X bills Client Q in May for the agreed upon amount of $5,000. The sales invoice shows that the amount will be due in June.\n In June, Company X receives the $5,000. What is the effect on the accounting equation and which accounts are affected at Company X? Liabilities","selection":["Increase","Decrease","No effect"],"answer":"No effect"},{"qID":"5.9|hard","question":"ABC purchases five mowers for $10,000 and finances them with a note from the local bank.","selection":["Owners equity increase and liabilities decrease","Asset decrease and Owners equity decrease",""],"answer":"Asset increase and Liabilities increase"}]},"6":{"category":"ACCOUNTING PRINCIPLES","question_set":[{"qID":"6.0|hard","question":"A very large corporation's financial statements have the dollar amounts rounded to the nearest $1,000. Which accounting principle/guideline justifies not reporting the amounts to the penny?","selection":["Full disclosure","Materiality","Monetary unit"],"answer":"Materiality"},{"qID":"6.1|hard","question":"When the accountant has to choose between two acceptable alternatives, the accountant should select the alternative that will report less profit, less asset amount, or a greater liability amount. This is based upon which principle/guideline?","selection":["Conservatism ","Cost","Materiality"],"answer":"Conservatism"},{"qID":"6.2|hard","question":"Public utilities' balance sheets list the plant assets before the current assets. This is acceptable under which accounting principle/guideline?","selection":["Conservatism","Cost","Industry practices"],"answer":"Industry practices"},{"qID":"6.3|hard","question":"A large company purchases a $250 digital camera and expenses it immediately instead of recording it as an asset and depreciating it over its useful life. This practice may be acceptable because of which principle/guideline?","selection":["Cost","Matching","Materiality"],"answer":"Materiality"},{"qID":"6.4|hard","question":"A corporation pays its annual property tax bill of approximately $12,000 in one payment each December 28. During the year, the corporation's monthly income statements report Property Tax Expense of $1,000. This is an example of which accounting principle/guideline?","selection":["Conservatism","Matching","Monetary unit"],"answer":"Matching"},{"qID":"6.5|hard","question":"A company sold merchandise of $8,000 to a customer in December. The company's sales terms require the customer to pay the company in 30 days. The company's income statement reported the sale in December. This is proper under which accounting principle/guideline? ","selection":["Full disclosure","Monetary unit","Revenue recognition"],"answer":"Revenue recognition"},{"qID":"6.6|hard","question":"The creative chief executive of a corporation who is personally responsible for numerous inventions and innovations is not reported as an asset on the corporation's balance sheet. The accounting principle/guideline that prevents the corporation for reporting this person as an asset is","selection":["Conservatism","Cost","Going concern"],"answer":"Cost"},{"qID":"6.7|hard","question":"An asset with a cost of $120,000 is depreciated over its useful life of 10 years rather than expensing the entire amount when it is purchased. This complies with which principle/guideline?","selection":["Cost","Full disclosure","Matching"],"answer":"Matching"},{"qID":"6.8|hard","question":"Near the end of the current year, a company required a customer to pay $200,000 as a deposit for work that is to begin in the following year. At the end of the current year the company reported the $200,000 as a liability on its balance sheet. Which accounting principle/guideline prevented the company from reporting the $200,000 on its income statement for the current year?","selection":["Going concern","Materiality","Revue recognition"],"answer":"Revenue recognition"},{"qID":"6.9|hard","question":"A company borrowed $100,000 in December and will make its only payment for interest when the note comes due six months later. The total interest for the six months will be $3,600. On the December income statement the accountant reported Interest Expense of $600. This action was the result of which accounting principle/guideline?","selection":["Cost","Matching","Revenue recognition"],"answer":"Matching"}]},"7":{"category":"FINANCIAL ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"7.0|hard","question":"The U.S. government agency with authority over the financial reporting requirements of publicly traded corporations is the __________.","selection":["AICPA","FASB","SEC"],"answer":"SEC"},{"qID":"7.1|hard","question":"The non-government organization that researches and develops new accounting standards is the __________.","selection":["FASB ","AICPA","SEC"],"answer":"FASB"},{"qID":"7.2|hard","question":"Which financial statement uses the expanded accounting equation?","selection":["Income statement","Balance sheet","Cash flow statement"],"answer":"Balance sheet"},{"qID":"7.3|hard","question":"The accrual basis of accounting records revenues when they are:","selection":["Collected","Earned","Contracted"],"answer":"Earned"},{"qID":"7.4|hard","question":"The account format that displays debits, credits, balances, and headings.","selection":["General Journal","General Ledger","T-account"],"answer":"T-account"},{"qID":"7.5|hard","question":"The profitability of a company for a specified period of time is reported on the __________ statement. ","selection":["Expenses","Income","Drawing"],"answer":"Income"},{"qID":"7.6|hard","question":"Prepaid insurance is reported as an __________on a company's balance sheet","selection":["Asset","Liabilities","Capital"],"answer":"Asset"},{"qID":"7.7|hard","question":"Which account increases equity?","selection":["Expenses","Withdrawals","Revenues"],"answer":"Revenues"},{"qID":"7.8|hard","question":"The main components or elements of the income statement are __________,expenses, gains, and losses. ","selection":["Expenses","Revenues","Net income"],"answer":"Revenues"},{"qID":"7.9|hard","question":"The statement of cash flows explains the changes in cash and cash __________ during the specified time interval. ","selection":["Equal","Percentage","Equivalent"],"answer":"Equivalent"}]},"8":{"category":"ADJUSTING ENTRIES","question_set":[{"qID":"8.0|hard","question":"The principle which dictates that efforts be matched with accomplishments is the:","selection":["Matching principle","Cost principle","Periodicity principle"],"answer":"Matching principle"},{"qID":"8.1|hard","question":"A bank lent $100,000 to a customer on December 1 that required the customer to pay an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12% on the amount of the loan. The loan is due in six months and no payment of interest or principal is to be made until the note is due on May 31. The bank prepares monthly financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that the bank will be making for its accounting records. What date should be used to record the December adjusting entry?","selection":["December 1 ","May 31","December 31"],"answer":"December 31"},{"qID":"8.2|hard","question":"A bank lent $100,000 to a customer on December 1 that required the customer to pay an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12% on the amount of the loan. The loan is due in six months and no payment of interest or principal is to be made until the note is due on May 31. The bank prepares monthly financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that the bank will be making for its accounting records. How many accounts are involved in the adjusting entry?","selection":["One","Two","Three"],"answer":"Two"},{"qID":"8.3|hard","question":"A bank lent $100,000 to a customer on December 1 that required the customer to pay an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12% on the amount of the loan. The loan is due in six months and no payment of interest or principal is to be made until the note is due on May 31. The bank prepares monthly financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that the bank will be making for its accounting records. What is the name of the account that should be debited?","selection":["Account receivable","Interest income","Interest receivable"],"answer":"Interest receivable"},{"qID":"8.4|hard","question":"A company borrowed $100,000 on December 1 by signing a six-month note that specifies interest at an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12%. No interest or principal payment is due until the note matures on May 31. The company prepares financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that should be entered in the company's records. What date should be used to record the December adjusting entry?","selection":["December 31","May 31","January 1"],"answer":"December 31"},{"qID":"8.5|hard","question":"A company borrowed $100,000 on December 1 by signing a six-month note that specifies interest at an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12%. No interest or principal payment is due until the note matures on May 31. The company prepares financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that should be entered in the company's records. How many accounts are involved in the adjusting entry?","selection":["One","Two","Three"],"answer":"Two"},{"qID":"8.6|hard","question":"A company borrowed $100,000 on December 1 by signing a six-month note that specifies interest at an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12%. No interest or principal payment is due until the note matures on May 31. The company prepares financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that should be entered in the company's records. What is the name of the account that will be debited?","selection":["Interest income","Interest expense","Interest receivable"],"answer":"Interest expenses"},{"qID":"8.7|hard","question":"A company borrowed $100,000 on December 1 by signing a six-month note that specifies interest at an annual percentage rate (APR) of 12%. No interest or principal payment is due until the note matures on May 31. The company prepares financial statements at the end of each calendar month. The following questions pertain to the adjusting entry that should be entered in the company's records. What is the name of the account that will be credited?","selection":["Interest accounts payable","Interest  notes payable","Interest payable"],"answer":"Interest payable"},{"qID":"8.8|hard","question":"A purchase of office supplies that was recorded in the Office Equipment account would require a correcting entry that.","selection":["Credit cash","Debits office equipment","Credit office equipment"],"answer":"Credit office equipment"},{"qID":"8.9|hard","question":"Reduction in a receivable or a payable that is granted if it is paid within the discount period.","selection":["Cash discount","Trade discount","Discount cash"],"answer":"Discount cash"}]},"9":{"category":"BALANCE SHEET","question_set":[{"qID":"9.0|hard","question":"Which of the following is a category or element of the balance sheet?","selection":["Expenses","Gains","Liabilities"],"answer":"Liabilities"},{"qID":"9.1|hard","question":"Which of the following is an asset account?","selection":["Accounts payable ","Prepaid insurance","Unearned revenue"],"answer":"Prepaid insurance"},{"qID":"9.2|hard","question":"Which of the following is a contra account?","selection":["Accumulated depreciation","Mary Smith Capital","Depreciation"],"answer":"Accumulated depreciation"},{"qID":"9.3|hard","question":"When an owner draws $5,000 from a sole proprietorship or when a corporation declares and pays a $5,000 dividend, the asset Cash decreases by $5,000. What is the other effect on the balance sheet?","selection":["Owner's/Stockholders' Equity Decreases ","None","Decrease Assets "],"answer":"Owner's/Stockholders' Equity Decreases"},{"qID":"9.4|hard","question":"Which of the following would not be a current asset?","selection":["Account receivable","Land","Supplies"],"answer":"Land"},{"qID":"9.5|hard","question":"ABC Co. incurs cleanup expense of $500 on December 30. The supplier's invoice states that the $500 is due by January 10 and ABC will pay the invoice on January 9. ABC follows the accrual basis of accounting and its accounting year ends on December 31. What is the effect of the cleanup service on the December balance sheet of ABC? ","selection":["Asset decrease","Liabilities increase","No effects on Owners equity"],"answer":"Liabilities increase"},{"qID":"9.6|hard","question":"On December 1, ABC Co. hired Juanita Perez to begin working on January 2 at a monthly salary of $4,000. ABC's balance sheet of December 31 will show a liability of","selection":["$4,000 ","$48,000 ","No Liability"],"answer":"No Liability "},{"qID":"9.7|hard","question":"Deferred credits will appear on the balance sheet with the","selection":["Asset","Liabilities","Owner's/Stockholders' Equity "],"answer":"Liabilities"},{"qID":"9.8|hard","question":"ABC Co. has current assets of $50,000 and total assets of $150,000. ABC has current liabilities of $30,000 and total liabilities of $80,000. What is the amount of ABC's owner's equity?","selection":["$20000","$30000","$70000"],"answer":"$70000"},{"qID":"9.9|hard","question":"Notes Payable could not appear as a line on the balance sheet in which classification?","selection":["Current asset","Current liabilities","long-term Liabilities"],"answer":"Current asset"}]},"10":{"category":"INCOME STATEMENT","question_set":[{"qID":"10.0|hard","question":"Which of the following names is NOT associated with the income statement? ","selection":["P & L ","Statement Of Financial Position","Statement Of Operations"],"answer":"Statement Of Financial Position "},{"qID":"10.1|hard","question":"A company disposes of equipment that it no longer uses in its business. The amount received by the company is more than the amount the asset is carried at in the accounting records. The company will report a(n) ","selection":["Expense ","Gain","Loss"],"answer":"Gain"},{"qID":"10.2|hard","question":"Is a retailer's Interest Expense an operating expense or a non-operating expense? ","selection":["Operating expenses","Non-operating expenses","Operating income"],"answer":"No-operating expenses"},{"qID":"10.3|hard","question":"A gain or loss that is unusual in nature and infrequent in occurrence is a(n)","selection":["Discounted operation","Extra ordinary item","Change in accounting principle"],"answer":"Discontinued Operation"},{"qID":"10.4|hard","question":"Interest earned on investments would appear in which section of a retailer's multiple-step income statement? ","selection":["Non-operating","Operating","Would not appear"],"answer":"None-operating"},{"qID":"10.5|hard","question":"The income statement line gross profit will appear on which income statement format?","selection":["Single-step ","Multiple-step ","Triple-step"],"answer":"Multiple-step"},{"qID":"10.6|hard","question":"Net Sales minus the Cost of Goods Sold equals ","selection":["Gross profit","Income form operation","Net income"],"answer":"Gross profit"},{"qID":"10.7|hard","question":"The combination of Selling Expenses and Administrative Expenses is referred to as","selection":["General expenses","Total expenses","Operating expenses"],"answer":"Operating Expenses"},{"qID":"10.8|hard","question":"When a company changes its book depreciation from an accelerated method to the straight-line method, it is considered to be a(n)","selection":["Discontinue operation","Extraordinary item","Change in accounting principles"],"answer":"Change in accounting principles"},{"qID":"10.9|hard","question":"The income statement format that segregates the operating revenues and expenses from the non-operating revenues and expenses is the ","selection":["Single-step","Multiple-step","Triple-step"],"answer":"Multiple-step"}]},"11":{"category":"BANK RECONCILIATION","question_set":[{"qID":"11.0|hard","question":"Interest earned by the business for money invested in the bank. Usually earned through a cash management account or term deposits. This is shown in the bank statement in the credit column.","selection":["Direct deposits","Interest revenue","Bank statement"],"answer":"Interest revenue"},{"qID":"11.1|hard","question":"Circled amounts in the previous bank reconciliation statement are entered into this document at the end of the bank reconciliation process. ","selection":["Bank statement ","Current bank statement","Current bank reconciliation statement"],"answer":"Current bank reconciliation statement"},{"qID":"11.2|hard","question":"The previous bank reconciliation statement should be checked with this record at the beginning of the bank reconciliation process. ","selection":["Bank statement","Current statement","current bank reconciliation statement"],"answer":"Current bank statement"},{"qID":"11.3|hard","question":"The business can authorise the bank to accept deposits on its behalf. Only whent the bank statement is issued does the business receive confirmation of the increase in its deposits. Rent Revenue is commonly deposited directly into the business's bank account. ","selection":["Direct deposits","Interest revenue","Bank statement"],"answer":"Direct deposits"},{"qID":"11.4|hard","question":"Document produced by the bank which shows the cash held by a business with the bank. It lists the deposits, withdrawals and balance of the business's bank account over a stated time period usually one month. ","selection":["Direct deposits","Interest revenue","Bank statement"],"answer":"Bank statement"},{"qID":"11.5|hard","question":"Which of the following items will require a journal entry to the company's books?","selection":["Bank service charge","Deposit in transit","Bank error"],"answer":"Bank service charge"},{"qID":"11.6|hard","question":"Which of the following will NOT require a journal entry to the company's books?","selection":["Checking printing charge","Outstanding checks","Fee For NSF Check"],"answer":"Outstanding checks"},{"qID":"11.7|hard","question":"A company recorded its check #2754 in its accounting records as $98. However, check #2754 was actually written for $89 and it cleared the bank as $89. What adjustment is needed to the Cash balance per books?","selection":["Decrease By $9","Increase By $9","None Needed"],"answer":"Increase By $9"},{"qID":"11.8|hard","question":"A company recorded its August 15 receipts on its books as $165. However, the receipts were actually $156. The deposit slip for the bank was prepared correctly as $156. What adjustment is needed to the Cash balance per books?","selection":["Decrease By $9","Increase By $9","None Needed"],"answer":"Decrease By $9"},{"qID":"11.9|hard","question":"A company deposited a check from a customer into its checking account. A few days later the check was returned with the notation account closed and the bank deducted the amount on the bank statement.","selection":["Add","Deduct","Balance"],"answer":"Deduct"}]},"12":{"category":"ACCOUNTS PAYABLE","question_set":[{"qID":"12.0|hard","question":"If a purchase is made from a supplier on credit, the account debited is? ","selection":["Accounts payable","Purchases","Cash"],"answer":"Purchases"},{"qID":"12.1|hard","question":"Suppose an invoice is received for Â£2,000 2% 15 days, net 30 terms. What is the discount taken if paid in 14 days? ","selection":["400 ","40","0"],"answer":"40"},{"qID":"12.2|hard","question":"What are trade accounts payable? ","selection":["Amounts owed to cash suppliers","Amounts owed to customers","Amounts owed to trade credit suppliers"],"answer":"Amounts owed to trade credit suppliers"},{"qID":"12.3|hard","question":" A discount of 2% for paying within 10 days instead of 30 days amounts to an annual percentage rate closest to","selection":["2%","24%","36%"],"answer":"36%"},{"qID":"12.4|hard","question":"Accounts payable is used in which ratio? ","selection":["Current ratio","Fixed assets turnover ratio","Current asset"],"answer":"Current ratio"},{"qID":"12.5|hard","question":"The accounts payable subsidiary ledger should be reconciled to which account?","selection":["Cash control","Accounts payable control ","Accounts receivable control"],"answer":"Accounts payable control"},{"qID":"12.6|hard","question":"When an auditor finds a debit to accounts payable, which of the following accounts is most likely to be credited? ","selection":[" Accounts Receivable.","Accrued liabilities.","Cash"],"answer":"Cash"},{"qID":"12.7|hard","question":"What reports are updated when you post the vouchers to the AP file?","selection":["Open AP, Cash Requirement, Vedor History reports","Voucher Edit, Open AP, Vendor Master File","Vendor & PO register, Open AP, Vendor Edit report"],"answer":"Open AP, Cash Requirement, Vedor History reports"},{"qID":"12.8|hard","question":"Paying the insurance premium on December 20 for the six-month period beginning 12 days later should result in a debit balance in the asset account __________ Insurance.","selection":["Unpaid","Prepaid","Cash"],"answer":"Prepaid"},{"qID":"12.9|hard","question":"The segregation or separation of duties and the safeguarding of checks are two examples of an important topic known as __________ controls.","selection":["Internal","External","All of the above"],"answer":"Internal"}]},"13":{"category":"INVENTORY COST OF GOOD SOLD","question_set":[{"qID":"13.0|hard","question":"The inventory cost flow assumption where the cost of the most recent purchase is matched first against sales revenues is ","selection":["FIFO","LIFO","Average"],"answer":"LIFO"},{"qID":"13.1|hard","question":"The inventory cost flow assumption where the oldest cost of inventory items is likely to remain on the balance sheet is ","selection":["FIFO ","LIFO","Average"],"answer":"LIFO"},{"qID":"13.2|hard","question":"The account Inventory will appear on the balance sheet as a current asset at an amount that often reflects the __________ of the merchandise on hand. ","selection":["Cost","Sales value","None of the above"],"answer":"Cost"},{"qID":"13.3|hard","question":"The inventory system that does NOT update the Inventory account automatically at the time of each purchase or sales is the _______________ method/system.","selection":["Perpetual","Periodic","None of the above"],"answer":"Perpetual"},{"qID":"13.4|hard","question":"A company purchased items for inventory during 2015 at continuously higher costs. Its last two purchases of 2015 were 20 units on December 20 at a cost of $14 per unit and 30 units on December 30 at a cost of $15 per unit. On December 28, 2015 the company made its last sale for the year when it sold 10 units. Which inventory cost flow assumption will cause the $15 cost per unit to be expensed as part of the year 2015's cost of goods sold? ","selection":["LIFO Periodic","LIFO Perpetual","Neither"],"answer":"LIFO Periodic"},{"qID":"13.5|hard","question":"A company has properly recorded all of its purchases of merchandise inventory, but made an error when counting its ending inventory. As a result of the error the company's Inventory account is overstated by $24,000. (This means that the amount in the Inventory account is too high by $24,000.) What is the impact of this error on the company's income statement? Specifically, the company's reported profit (ignoring income tax expense) in the period of the error is...","selection":["Too high","Too low","Not affected"],"answer":"Too High"},{"qID":"13.6|hard","question":"The inventory cost flow assumption where the cost of the most recent purchases are likely to remain in inventory","selection":["FIFO","LIFO","Average"],"answer":"FIFO"},{"qID":"13.7|hard","question":"A company in the computer industry is experiencing continuously lower costs. Which cost flow assumption will result in less income tax expense for this company?","selection":["FIFO","LIFO","Average"],"answer":"FIFO"},{"qID":"13.8|hard","question":"A retailer's inventory cost should include freight-in on the merchandise purchased with terms ______ shipping point?","selection":["FOB","FIFO","LIFO"],"answer":"FOB"},{"qID":"13.9|hard","question":"Net Purchases is Gross Purchases minus Purchase Returns and Allowances and _____________.","selection":["Purchase discount","Sales discount","Merchandise"],"answer":"Purchase discount"}]},"14":{"category":"DEPRECIATION","question_set":[{"qID":"14.0|hard","question":"What type of assets are depreciated? ","selection":["Plant","Current","None of the above"],"answer":"Plant"},{"qID":"14.1|hard","question":"Which of the following is a plant asset?","selection":["Supplies ","Track","Merchandise inventory"],"answer":"Truck"},{"qID":"14.2|hard","question":"What type of account is accumulated depreciation? ","selection":["Current asset","Plant asset","Contra plant asset"],"answer":"Contra plant asset"},{"qID":"14.3|hard","question":"What does the net pay control account represent?","selection":["The gross wages and salaries expense","An amount due to the employee for wages and salaries","An amount due from the employee for tax owed"],"answer":"An amount due to the employee for wages and salaries"},{"qID":"14.4|hard","question":"Is the gross pay account an income statement , balance sheet account or account receivable? ","selection":["Income statement","Balance sheet","Account receivable"],"answer":"Income statement"},{"qID":"14.5|hard","question":"The book value of an asset is defined as","selection":["Cost Minus Salvage Value","Cost Minus Accumulated Depreciation. ","Estimated Fair Market Value"],"answer":"Cost Minus Accumulated Depreciation."},{"qID":"14.6|hard","question":"What are unpaid wages?","selection":["Amounts earned by the employee but not paid at the end of the accounting period.","An estimate of wages for the next accounting period.",""],"answer":"Amounts earned by the employee but not paid at the end of the accounting period."},{"qID":"14.7|hard","question":"What does the employee tax control account represent?","selection":["A liability to the tax authority for tax deducted from employees gross pay.","An amount due from the employee for tax owed.","none of the above"],"answer":"A liability to the tax authority for tax deducted from employees gross pay."},{"qID":"14.8|hard","question":"When the employer pays the employee in 2016 for the vacation earned in 2015, what account will the company debit?","selection":["Cash","Vacation Expense","Vacation Payable"],"answer":"Vacation Payable"},{"qID":"14.9|hard","question":"Which of the following depreciation methods is NOT an accelerated method?","selection":["Sum-of-the-years' Digits","Straight-line","Double-declining Balance"],"answer":"Straight-line"}]},"15":{"category":"PAYROLL ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"15.0|hard","question":"Unpaid wages are accrued for by a debit to which of the following accounts? ","selection":["Accrual for wages","Gross pay","Net pay control"],"answer":"Gross pay"},{"qID":"15.1|hard","question":"The 2016 rate for the Social Security tax (excluding the Medicare tax) that is withheld from employees' salaries and wages up to a specified annual amount is __________%. ","selection":["6.2 ","6.4","6.3"],"answer":"6.2"},{"qID":"15.2|hard","question":"The combined rate for the Social Security tax and the Medicare tax to be withheld from each employee's gross wages up to $118,500 in 2016 is __________%.","selection":["6.75%","7.62%","7.65% "],"answer":"7.65%"},{"qID":"15.3|hard","question":"The pay earned by hourly-paid employees is usually referred to as __________.","selection":["Wages","Accounts payable","Salaries"],"answer":"Wages"},{"qID":"15.4|hard","question":"The pay earned by managers who are paid semi-monthly is referred to as __________.","selection":["Wages","Accounts payable","Salary or salaries"],"answer":"Salary or salaries"},{"qID":"15.5|hard","question":"Which employee payroll classification will likely require an accrual adjusting entry for the gross salaries or wages at the end of a calendar month?","selection":["Exempt Salaried Employees Paid Semi-monthly","Hourly Employees Paid Weekly ","All of the above"],"answer":"Hourly Employees Paid Weekly"},{"qID":"15.6|hard","question":"An employee is hired at a pay rate of $10 per hour. During the past week, the employee worked 50 hours. The employeeâ€™s gross wages for the past week are","selection":["$400","$550","$450"],"answer":"$550"},{"qID":"15.7|hard","question":"The amount that an employee \"clears\" or \"takes home\" is the __________ pay.","selection":["Cash on hand","Net","Account receivable"],"answer":"Net"},{"qID":"15.8|hard","question":"A tax paid by the employer that is 0.6% of each employeeâ€™s first $7,000 of annual salary or wages is __________ tax.","selection":["Federal employment","Employment","None of the above"],"answer":"Federal employment"},{"qID":"15.9|hard","question":"The federal form on which an employee indicates the number of exemptions/dependents to be used in calculating the amount of federal income tax withholding for the employee is the __________ form.","selection":["W-4","W-5","W-6"],"answer":"W-4"}]},"16":{"category":"STOCKHOLDER EQUITY","question_set":[{"qID":"16.0|hard","question":"One of the advantages of the corporation form of business as opposed to a partnership form is the ease of transferring __________. ","selection":["Article in incorporation","Ownership","Stockholders equity"],"answer":"Ownership"},{"qID":"16.1|hard","question":"At a corporation, Assets minus Liabilities is __________. ","selection":["Stockholders equity ","Equity","Owners"],"answer":"Stockholders equity"},{"qID":"16.2|hard","question":"The type of stock that gets its dividend before the common stock gets its dividend is called __________ stock. ","selection":["Common","Preferred","Outstanding"],"answer":"Preferred)"},{"qID":"16.3|hard","question":"If a corporation has issued only one type of stock, it is __________ stock.","selection":["Common","Preferred","Outstanding"],"answer":"Outstanding"},{"qID":"16.4|hard","question":"Shares of stock that have been issued and have not been reacquired by the issuing corporation are called __________ shares.","selection":["Common","Preferred","Outstanding"],"answer":"Common"},{"qID":"16.5|hard","question":"If a common stock does not have a par value or a stated value, the entire proceeds from issuing the stock is credited to one account entitled _______.","selection":["Cumulative","Treasury stock ","Common stock"],"answer":"Common stock"},{"qID":"16.6|hard","question":"The par value of _______ stock usually has no economic significance.","selection":["Common","Debit","Record"],"answer":"Common"},{"qID":"16.7|hard","question":"If a corporation declares a small stock dividend, the account that will be reduced by a debit entry is _______.","selection":["Convertible","Outstanding","Retained earnings"],"answer":"Retained earnings"},{"qID":"16.8|hard","question":"If a share of treasury stock is sold for more than its cost, the difference is credited to _______.","selection":["Paid-in capital and retained earnings","Treasury stock","Paid-in capital from treasury stock"],"answer":"Paid-in capital from treasury stock"},{"qID":"16.9|hard","question":"Dividends in arrears occur only on _______ preferred stock.","selection":["Convertible","Declaration","Board of directors"],"answer":"Convertible"}]},"17":{"category":"NONPROFIT ACCOUNTING","question_set":[{"qID":"17.0|hard","question":"A nonprofit's revenues and expenses are reported on its statement of __________. ","selection":["Cash flows","Activities","Financial position"],"answer":"Activities"},{"qID":"17.1|hard","question":"A nonprofit's assets and liabilities are reported on its statement of __________. ","selection":["Cash flows ","Activities","Financial position"],"answer":"Financial position"},{"qID":"17.2|hard","question":"The classifications for reporting contributions according to the donors' stipulations are unrestricted, __________ restricted, and permanently restricted. ","selection":["Temporarily","Partially","Permanently"],"answer":"Temporarily"},{"qID":"17.3|hard","question":"Classifying expenses into program activities and supporting activities is known as the _______________ basis.","selection":["Functional","Natural","None of the above"],"answer":"Functional"},{"qID":"17.4|hard","question":"Reporting expenses by categories such as salaries, rent, utilities, etc. is known as the _______________ basis.","selection":["Functional","Natural","None of the above"],"answer":"Natural"},{"qID":"17.5|hard","question":"The two types of restrictions on contributions that are classified as temporarily restricted are purpose and __________.","selection":["Period of time","Point in time ","Time"],"answer":"Time"},{"qID":"17.6|hard","question":"A nonprofit's expenses are reported as part of the changes in ___________________ net assets.","selection":["Unrestricted","Temporary restricted","Permanently restricted"],"answer":"Unrestricted"},{"qID":"17.7|hard","question":"Normally the principal portion of an endowment will be classified as _________________ net assets.","selection":["Unrestricted","Temporary restricted","Permanently restricted"],"answer":"Permanently restricted"},{"qID":"17.8|hard","question":"A nonprofit organization's assets that have been designated by its board of directors for a specific project should be reported on the external financial statements as__________________ net assets.","selection":["Unrestricted","Permanently restricted","Temporary restricted"],"answer":"Unrestricted"},{"qID":"17.9|hard","question":"Which form of financing is allowed for a nonprofit organization?","selection":["Debt","Sale Of Equity Securities","Both Are Allowed"],"answer":"Debt"}]}}}